swarmation.com 2008-12-06

# Swarmation

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Swarmation collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Swarmation’ s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Swarmation’ s visitors use its website. From time to time, Swarmation may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Swarmation also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Swarmation does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Swarmation’ s websites choose to interact with Swarmation in ways that require Swarmation to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Swarmation gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up to provide a username and email address. In any case, Swarmation collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’ s interaction with Swarmation. Swarmation does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Swarmation may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Swarmation may monitor the most popular blogs on the Swarmation.com site. Swarmation may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Swarmation does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Swarmation discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Swarmation’ s behalf or to provide services available at Swarmation’ s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Swarmation’ s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Swarmation will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Swarmation discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Swarmation believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Swarmation, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Swarmation website and have supplied your email address, Swarmation may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’ s going on with Swarmation and our products. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Swarmation takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’ s computer, and that the visitor’ s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Swarmation uses cookies to help Swarmation identify and track visitors, their usage of Swarmation website, and their website access preferences. Swarmation visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Swarmation’ s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Swarmation’ s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Swarmation may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Swarmation’ s sole discretion. Swarmation encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
